Lumbard, Eliot H.; Papers apap071
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Lumbard, Eliot H. Papers
1943-2006
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Lumbard, Eliot H.
apap071
52.15 cubic ft.
This collection documents the professional and personal life of Eliot H. Lumbard.
Collection X
Access
This collection is unrestricted with the exception of select folders in Series 7, Subseries 2.
Acquisition Information
Beginning in 1972 and continuing during the mid 1970s, Eliot H. Lumbard donated portions of this manuscript group to the University at Albany. Lumbard transfered additonal materials in 1999, 2005, and 2006 to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives. Martin Greenberg deposited additional accessions in 2002.
Historical Note
Eliot Howland Lumbard practiced law for 40 years as an associate or partner in various New York and Pennsylvania firms. In addition to his private practice, he compiled a distinguished record in government service, including service on several commissions to investigate, combat, and control crime, and as a key advisor on crime to New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller.
Lumbard was born in Fairhaven, Mass. on May 6, 1925. He received a B.S. from the Merchant Marine Academy in 1945 after serivce in World War II, a B.S. in Economics from the Wharton School of Finance and Commerce at the University of Pennsylvania in 1949 and his J.D. from Columbia University in 1952. He was admitted to the New York State Bar in 1953 and the U. S. Supreme Court Bar in 1959. In addition, in 2005 he received an honorary Doctorate of Science from the United States Merchant Marine Academy.
Following his admission to the Bar, he began his legal career in government service. From 1953-1956 he was an Assistant United States Attorney in the Southern District of New York. During this time, he was assigned to a wide variety of both civil and criminal matters. From 1958-1961 he was Chief Counsel of the New York State Commission of Investigation. New York Governor W. Averell Harriman signed the Commission of Investigation into law on April 25, 1958 and charged the Commission with the duty and power to conduct investigations in connection with organized crime and racketeering, the conduct of public officers and public employees and any matter concerning the public peace, public safety and public justice. In his role, Lumbard organized and directed many large and complex investigations, including the investigation of the police departments in Buffalo, Rochester, and Syracuse, as well as investigating organized crime, harness racing, bingo, the New York City school construction program, and Albany real estate tax delinquencies. In 1961 New York Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller hired Lumbard as Special Assistant Counsel for Law Enforcement, a position he held until 1967. As a key Rockefeller advisor, Lumbard discussed many ideas and issues related to the social problems of crime and crime control. Lumbard organized the Oyster Bay Conferences on Organized Crime (1963-1967), developed the New York State Information and Intelligence System (NYSIIS) which was the first computer-based criminal justice record system that included individual criminal histories, and proposed creating a school of criminal justice, eventually established at the University at Albany in 1965.
During his career in private practice, Lumbard worked on many cases of commercial litigation on finance and bankruptcy matters. Some of his cases included: counsel to Charles Seligson and trustee in bankruptcy of Ira Haupt and Co. (1964-1973), a large Wall Street case known as the salad oil debacle in 1963; trustee in bankruptcy of Universal Money Order Co., Inc. (1977-1982) which was the nation’s largest consumer bankruptcy; and trustee in the Roy Cohn proceedings who was accused of professional misconduct. In the early 1970s, he represented the Center for Reproductive and Sexual Health (CRASH), located in New York City and at the time the largest freestanding abortion clinic in the world. CRASH opened in 1970 after New York legalized abortion.
Lumbard worked in academe as a lecturer at the New York University Law School from 1963-1965 and as an Adjunct Professor of Law and Criminal Justice at John Jay College from 1975-1985. From 1967-1969, Lumbard researched and wrote an unpublished work titled Harm to Each Other: Crime and Crime Control in America.
In addition, Lumbard served as director or trustee of many organizations, including the New York Police Foundation, Inc. (1971-1991) and the New York State Maritime Museum (1969-1980). Lumbard was a member of many professional organizations, including the Association of the Bar of the City of New York, the International Bar Association, the New York Bar Association, and the American Bar Association.
Lumbard died in November 2013 at the age of 88 in Nashua, NH and was survived by two daughters and a son.
Scope and Contents
The Eliot Lumbard Papers document the life’s work of a lawyer who devoted himself towards both public service and private practice with equal vigor and success. The collection is arranged into 12 series: Series 1: Office of the U.S. Attorney, Southern District of New York; Series 2: New York State Commission of Investigation; Series 3: Special Assistant Counsel for Law Enforcement to New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller; Series 4: Other Public Service, Professional Associations and Organizations; Series 5:Publications, Harm to Each Other: Crime Control in America; Series 6: Other Publications; Series 7: Private Practice; Series 8: Teaching; Series 9: Correspondence; Series 10: Personal Files; Series 11: Subject Files; Series 12: Audio/Visual. Series 7 is further divided into two subseries.
The Lumbard papers are useful to scholars, students and historians studying New York State government of the 1960s, bankruptcy cases, SUNY Albany, and criminal justice. The entire collection totaling nearly 53 cubic feet contains records from his public and private sector work which he had commercially bound. The collection includes: correspondence, memorandum, press releases, reports, court proceedings, notes, speeches, journal articles, academic papers, drafts, newspaper clippings, and background research.
All of the significant positions that Lumbard held are represented in this collection including his service as Assistant U.S. Attorney 1953-1956, Chief Counsel for the New York State Commission of Investigation, 1958-1961, and Special Assistant Counsel for Law Enforcement to New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1961-1967. Also of significant interest are his records from private practice cases including: counsel to Charles Seligson and trustee in bankruptcy of Ira Haupt and Co. (1964-1973); formation of the University at Albany’s School of Criminal Justice; review panel to disbar to Roy Cohn, accused of professional misconduct; and representation of the Center for Reproductive and Sexual Health in the early 1970s.
Access to some individual legal case files in Series 7 are restricted. Consult the head of the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives for details.
Lumbard, Eliot H.; New York (State)--Politics and government; Law enforcement-- New York (State); Practice of law--New York (State); Correspondence; Legal documents; Manuscripts for publication; Albany, New York; Criminal Justice and Prisons; Public Servants
- Office of the U.S. Attorney, Southern District of New York, 1952-1989; 1; 2.06 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of records from Lumbard’s position as Assistant United States Attorney in the Southern District of New York. During this time, Lumbard was assigned to a wide variety of both civil and criminal matters. This series includes memoranda, news clippings, trial briefs, procedures, and forms.
  - Bicentennial of the U.S. Attorneys for the Southern District of New York, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Briefs and Records - Volume 1, Undated (Oversized 1)
  - Briefs and Records - Volume 2, Undated (Oversized 1)
  - Briefs and Records - Volume 3, Undated (Oversized 2)
  - Briefs and Records - Volume 4, Undated (Oversized 7)
  - Briefs and Records - Volume 12, Undated (Oversized 3)
  - Corresp., Directories, Performance Reviews, and Resignation Letters, 1952-1956; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Directory of Assistant U.S. Attorneys in the Southern District of New York, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - First Report of the NYS Crime Commission, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Handbook of the Civil Division of the U.S. Attorneys Office Southern District of New York"/w Corresp. and Notes (1 of 3), 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Handbook of the Civil Division of the US Attorneys Office Southern District of New York"/w Corresp. and Notes (2 of 3), 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Handbook of the Civil Division of the US Attorneys Office Southern District of New York"/w Corresp. and Notes (3 of 3), 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lumbard's Cardboard Name Plaques, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Proving Federal Crimes," Second Edition Draft w/ Corresp. and Notes (1 of 3), 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Proving Federal Crimes," Second Edition Draft w/ Corresp. and Notes (2 of 3), 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Proving Federal Crimes," Second Edition Draft w/ Corresp. and Notes (3 of 3), 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Reassignment and Closing Memoranda, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Tax Investigation, 1954 -1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - United States Attorney's Office for the Southern District of New York - Selected Memoranda, Trial Briefs, Procedures, and Forms - Volume 1, 1953-1956 (Oversized 4)
  - United States Attorney's Office for the Southern District of New York - Selected Memoranda, Trial Briefs, Procedures, and Forms - Volume 2, 1953-1956 (Oversized 5)
  - United States Attorney's Office for the Southern District of New York - Selected Memoranda, Trial Briefs, Procedures, and Forms - Volume 4, 1953-1956 (Oversized 6)
- New York State Commission of Investigation, 1955-1991; 2; 5.43 cubic ft.
  This series consists of records from Lumbard’s position as chief counsel for the New York State Commission of Investigations. During this time, Lumbard organizied and directed many large and complex investigations. This series contains records of investigations of police departments, organized crime, and gambling. It includes notes, memoranda, correspondence, speeches, reports, press releases, news clippings, court proceedings, and public hearings.
  - Attorney General: Duties, Memos, Report, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Attorney's Resume, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Briefs and Records- Application of Investigation to Commit F.J. Valenti, Mancuso, Riccobono, Castellano, Miranda, Lombardozzi, and C.P. Valenti - Volume 5, Undated (Oversized 8)
  - Briefs and Records- Application of Investigation to Commit F.J. Valenti, Mancuso, Riccobono, Castellano, Miranda, Lombardozzi, and C.P. Valenti - Volume 6, Undated (Oversized 9)
  - Briefs and Records- Application of Investigation to Commit F.J. Valenti, Mancuso, Riccobono, Castellano, Miranda, Lombardozzi, and C.P. Valenti - Volume 10, Undated (Oversized 9)
  - Civil Service- Notes- Memos, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Law Enforcement- Notes, 1959 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Conference, 1958-1959; 1971; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and EHL Registration, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and Newsclippings, 1983-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Discrimination Complaints - Memos- Notes, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - District Attorney Convention- Report - Original Draft, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Eavesdropping Procedures, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Election Law - Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - First Report to Governor and Legislature of NY, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Immunity- Notes, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Internal Revenue Service - Conference- Notes, 1958 July 23 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Interviews- Staff - Notes, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - An Investigation of Law Enforcement in Buffalo, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Investigation Procedures- Statement by Mayor Robert Wagner 1960, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Investigators- Applications- Assessments, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Judge J. Irwin Shapiro- Address, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Legislative Crime Investigation Commissions in Five States", 1960 August (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Legislative Programs- Memos- Notes, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Litigation- Assignment Lists, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Mary Krone Investigation, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meetings- Notes, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The NYC Prisoner Release, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - New York State Library- Interviews, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - News Releases, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper- Editorial Writers, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Policy - Resolutions, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Proposed Budget Request, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Questionnaire- Memos, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Quinn - Notes- Memos, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Report- Improving Westchester County Police, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Reports, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Salaries - Lists, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Speeches - Outlines, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Staff Meetings- Notes - Memos, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - State of New York - Commission of Investigation - Agenda, 1958 July 22-1961 January 31 (Oversized 10)
  - State of New York - Commission of Investigation - Annual Reports, 1970-1974 (Oversized 19)
  - State of New York - Commission of Investigation - Hearing Rules Commission, Memoranda Staff Handbook, Publicity, Undated (Oversized 11)
  - State of New York - Commission of Investigation - Litigation Memoranda - Volume 2, Undated (Oversized 12)
  - State of New York - Commission of Investigation - Outlines for Hearings about Conditions in the Buffalo Police Department (Public Hearings) and Ithaca Police Department (Private Hearings) - Volume 3, Undated (Oversized 13)
  - State of New York - Commission of Investigation - Reports - Volume 1, 1959-1965 (Oversized 15)
  - State of New York - Commission of Investigation - Reports - Volume 2, 1964-1974 (Oversized 14)
  - State of New York - Commission of Investigation - Reports - Volume 4, 1959-1961 (Oversized 15)
  - State of New York- Commission of Investigation - Reports - Volume 5, 1962-1966 (Oversized 16)
  - State of New York- Commission of Investigation - Reports - Volume 6, 1967-1974 (Oversized 16)
  - State Police Intelligence Unit- Memos, 1958 -1959 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Statistics- Tax - Notes - Memos, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Syndicated Gambling in NYS, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Use of Lie Detector, 1960 March 15 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Vacation Schedules, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Wessel Investigation- Subpoenas- Memos, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Wire Tapping Equipment- Memos, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Special Assistant Counsel for Law Enforcement to New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1956-1996; 3; 10.17 cubic ft.
  Arragned alphabetically.
  This series consists of records from Lumbard’s position as special assistant counsel for law enforcement to Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller of New York. Lumbard served the governor in many capacities. He was an advisor on the social problems of crime and crime control, as well as a liaison from the executive chamber to criminal justice agencies and the courts in New York State. This series contains records regarding the programs Lumbard organized and/or initiated including: the Oyster Bay Conference on Crime also known as the Governor’s Conference on Crime; the New York State Information and Intelligence System (NYSIIS); investigations into organized crime and gambling; and State Department of Crime Control. The series also contains correspondence, biographical information about Nelson A. Rockefeller, and research into issues such as racial violence, politics, and criminal justice.
  - "The Administration of Criminal Justice in NYS: An Appraisal and Recommendations for the Future," Draft (1 of 2), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Administration of Criminal Justice in NYS: An Appraisal and Recommendations for the Future," Draft (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administration of Criminal Justice in NY State, Excerpts- By- EHL, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Administration of Criminal Justice in NYS," Speech by EBL and Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Article about Rockefeller in Empire State Report, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Background Papers on Criminal Justice Admin. for the Suggested Revision of the NYS Constitution (not adopted), ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bibliography for Organized Crime, ca. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Civil Liberties and the War on Crime," Lecture by Gov. Kirk of Florida, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Civilian Review Board- News Releases- Report, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Combatting Organized Crime," Corresp. and Photos, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Constitutional Convention, Reports and Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1965 January-August (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1965 September-December (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence (1 of 3), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence (2 of 3), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence (3 of 3), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence (1 of 3), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence (2 of 3), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (3 of 3), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Corresp. abt. Law Enforcement, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence about Organized Crime, 1965-1967; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Robert Douglas, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with Sol Neil Corbin, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with Sol Neil Corbin, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Corruption- Grand Jury Associations, Reports and Newsclippings, 1956; 1959-1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Corruption in Massachusetts, Newsclippings, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Corruption, Newsclippings, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Crime Conference Booklets (1 of 2), 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Crime Conference Booklets (2 of 2), 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Crime Conferences, Notes, Research Material, and Press Releases, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Crime in NYS Summary Paper, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Crime Statements Meetings, Notes, and Correspondence about Research and Hearings, 1968; Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Crime Statistics, Press-Releases, Reports and Correspondence, 1962-1966; 1968; Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Criminal Justice, Goals and Notes, 1964; Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Criminal Justice News Clippings, Press Releases, and Corresp., 1970-1971; Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Criminal Justice News Releases, 1969-1971; Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Criminal Justice, Reports-Memos-Related Materials, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Criminal Law and Equal Justice" - by Charles D. Breitel and Press Releases about Crime by N. Rockefeller, 1964; 1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Criminal Legislation Newsclippings and Reports, 1964-1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "A Current Picture of Organized Crime," Central Investigation Bureau Training Bulletin 8, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Development of the New York State Identification and Intelligence System - Volume 1, 1963-1964
  - Development of the New York State Identification and Intelligence System - Volume 2, 1965-1966
  - Development of the New York State Identification and Intelligence System - Volume 3, 1967-1970
  - Development of the New York State Identification and Intelligence System - Volume 4, 1967-1970
  - FDIC Reports, 1964-1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Federal Agency Requests-Directorate-Memos on Organized Crime, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Federal Legislation- Program Status Report on Organized Crime Bills, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Federal Task Force on Organized Crime Reports, 1964; 1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Firearms, Press Release and Newsclippings, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Frank O'Connor - Research - Notes, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Frank Sedita- (Mayor of Buffalo) - Testimony - Memos, 1965; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Fraud, Newsclippings, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gambling and Off-Track Betting, Newsclippings and Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "The Gov't of NYS" and Rockefeller Inauguration Program, 1966; 1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Governor Rockefeller's Conference on Crime, 1966 April 21-2006 April 22
  - Governor's Committee to Review the Parole System of NY State Report, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Governor's Conference on Alcohol Problems, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Governor Rockefeller's Conference on Crime, Correspondence and Press Releases, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Governor Rockefeller's Conference on Crime, Follow Up- Notes- Correspondence, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Governor Rockefeller's Conference on Crime, Memos on Gov. Rockefeller's Appearance, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Governor Rockefeller's Conference on Crime, Participants, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Governor Rockefeller's Conference on Crime, Personal Notebook of Eliot Lumbard (1 of 2), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Governor Rockefeller's Conference on Crime, Personal Notebook of Eliot Lumbard (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Governor Rockefeller's Conference on Crime, Personal Notebook of Gov. Rockefeller (1 of 2), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Governor Rockefeller's Conference on Crime, Personal Notebook of Gov. Rockefeller (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Governor Rockefeller's Press Releases about Crime Justice Issues and Plans for Future Conferences, 1966; Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "Gov. Rockefeller's Special Committee on Criminal Offenders", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Gov. Rockefeller's Speech at 2nd Annual Convention of Queens Federation of Civic Councils, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Gov. Rockefeller's Speech on Gun Control and Research Materials, 1967-1969; Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Governor's Conference on Crime, Invitation and Schedule of Events, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Governors' Counsel Reunion Dinner, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Houston Crime Commission- Fifth Annual Report, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Howard J. Samuels - News Releases and Notes, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - IIT Research Institute, National Symposium on Law Enforcement Science and Technology, Correspond., Program, and Reports, and EHL's Speech (1 of 2), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - IIT Research Institute, National Symposium on Law Enforcement Science and Technology, Correspond., Program, and Reports, and EHL's Speech (2 of 2), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - International Association of Chiefs of Police - 72nd Annual Conference- Report on Organized Crime, 1965 October 2-7 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Interpol- Reports and Notes on Organized Crime, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Investigation of the Yonkers Raceway and M. Tanabaum, EBL's Notes, 1966; Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Juvenile Delinquency- Task Force Member, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - LEA Commission - Reports - Memos, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Legalization of Off-Track Betting in NYS, Correspondence and Report, 1959-1965 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Legislative Program on Criminal Justice, Memos-Notes- News Releases, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 31)